TYLER POEPPING

Lake Wylie, SC 29710 (803) 879-3816 - typoepping@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a 7 year Army veteran and aspiring software engineer. I departed the Army in March of 2022 and immediately enrolled in the University of Minnesota's Coding Bootcamp where I graduated in December of 2022. I started developing websites when I was in the Army and now have the opportunity to pursue a career in a field that I am very passionate about. I have much to offer as well as much to learn for a great company willing to give me a chance.

Pinned to my Github is examples of the skills listed on this resume: https://github.com /SSPENELOPE

SKILLS

- Software Engineering
- Full-Stack Web Development
- MERN Stack
- React.JS
- MongoDB
- MYSQL
- Node.JS
- Express.JS

- Handlebars
- Apollo
- GraphQL
- ASP.NET
- NET Core 6.0
- C#
- Azure
- Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio

WORK HISTORY

02/2018 to 03/2022 Training and Development Manager

US Army – Fort Benning, GA

- Compared training needs for a cross-functional team of 8 personnel to the needs of the organization; analyzed, interpreted, and validated those training systems for a 100-person organization
- Provided informal coaching and guidance to employees on remote systems that enabled them to fix operator level issues on the spot reducing pauses in machine functioning by 80%
- Evaluated organizational challenges through process gap analysis and crafted strategic talent management solutions; enhanced employee retention by 50%

02/2018 to 03/2022 **Personnel Manger**

US Army – Fort Benning, GA

- Conducted analysis of workforce modernization, programs for planning, resource allocation, acquisition, training and policy, performance monitoring, and reporting; delivered an impressive 87% operational readiness rate
- Selected by the Senior Personnel Manager to serve as the Department Manager for 12 weeks as a result of my knowledge, skills, and abilities
- Oversaw the maintenance, serviceability, and 100% accountability of over \$1.9M worth of organizational equipment with zero loss or damage

09/2015 to 02/2018 **Rifleman**

US Army – Vilseck, Germany

- Conducted reconnaissance operations to gather intelligence on enemy positions.
- Worked on fire team of 9 people to outmaneuver enemy forces.
- Patrolled designated coverage areas and evaluated terrain for defensive use.
- Trained teams on emergency situation preparedness and integration of tactical planning, equipment maintenance and weapon use.

EDUCATION

Continuing Education Courses: Software Engineering

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities - Online

- C-Sharp
- Java

12/2022

Certification: Fullstack Web Development

University of Minnesota - Twin Cities - Online

Attended University of Minnesota Coding Bootcamp from 12Jun2022 - 20Dec2022 and graduated with an overall grade of 94%.

05/2019

Certification: Basic Leadership And Operations Management

US Army - Fort Benning, GA

- Professional development completed in Basic Leadership and Operations Management
- Required certification and course to become a Non Commissioned Officer in the US Army

05/2015

High School Diploma

CENTENNIAL HIGHSCHOOL - Circle Pines, MN

- Dual Enrollment Student at Century College, Diesel Mechanics
- 4 Years German Language